# **Phung Hung Binh**

Ho Chi Minh City, Viet Nam | LinkedIn | +84 365668703 | Phunghungbinh.work@gmail.com

## **SUMMARY**

I am an automation Engineer who's knowledgeable in both computer science and electrical engineering. Work effectively in the Robotics Design field of research. Built a modelling and simulation Robot using Python/PyQt5 Framework. Dynamically adept at completing demanding projects within crucial timelines.

## **EDUCATION**

## **HCMC University of Technology and Education**

Thu Duc, Ho Chi Minh city

Control and Automation Engineering (GPA: 3.17/4.0)

09.2021

- University honor student Award in 2020-2021.
- Recipient of University Encourage Scholarships for top 10 highest GPA 2019-2021.
- Data Science Project: A High-Performance Nonlinear Neural Network on Speech Recognition module.
- Capstone Project: Designed and Operated six Degree of Freedoms Robotics model using speech command.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **HCMC University of Technology and Education**

Thu Duc, Ho Chi Minh city

Teaching Fellow for several courses

May 2019 - present

- Prepare syllabus and created course materials.
- Designed course lectures, maintained correspondence with under-graduate students.
- Organized Academic Competition: "Robot Fights 2020" for the University's students.

# **HCMUTE's Robotics Research Laboratory**

**HCMUTE**, Ho Chi Minh city

May 2020 - present

• Create and maintain Robotics GUI using Python Programming for Controlling Robot model used.

- Prepare presentations, manuscripts, abstracts, and co-author for publication.
- Perform technical duties for theoretical studies in the field of Robotics Framework and standard Neural Network Modelling.

#### DAT DO's services and Commercial, LLC

Binh Duong Province, Viet Nam

Associate – Mechanical Engineering

May 2020 - present

- Measure dimensions of finished workpieces to ensure conformance to specifications, using precision measuring instruments, templates and fixtures.
- Maintain safe operations by adhering to safety procedures and regulations.
- Utilized CNC machinery to manufacture custom drill bits for wide variety of applications.

# **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

Senior Research Assistant

## **Technical Skills:**

- Python/ PyQt5 module: GUI Programmed for Robotics Modelling and Simulation.
- Data visualization: Collected and Examined Loss Function Data, Error and Learning Rate of ML model.
- Linux, Raspbian Scripting: Built an Embedded system using Raspberry Pi module.
- providing an understanding and application of standard principles, theories, concepts and techniques in Robotics.
- Proficiency in scripting languages MATLAB and Python.
- Proficiency with CAD: Solidwork.

**Personal Interests:** Avid reader, gymnastics, volunteering

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

•	Assistance to AIESEC youth-run organization to develop <b>Gender Equality</b> Project.	August 2021 – Oct 2021
•	Certificate of Formal Presenter of virtual conference ICSSE 2021.	August 26-28, 2021
•	Scientific Computing with Python Verified by FreeCodeCamp.org	September 01, 2021
•	Completed Fundamental skill in Python Program Certified by HakerRank.	September 13, 2021
•	Completed Digital Body Language Certified by LinkedIn Learning	September 09, 2021

• completed the EF SET Certificate and has achieved C2 Proficient English level. September 27, 2021

# **PUBLICATIONS**

Neural Network Research: P. H. Binh, P. V. Hoang and D. X. Ba, "A High-Performance Speech-Recognition Method Based on a Nonlinear Neural Network,"

**Abstract**: 2021 International Conference on System Science and Engineering (**ICSSE**), 2021, pp. 96-100, doi: 10.1109/ICSSE52999.2021.9537942.

# **COMMUNITY SERVICE**

Gender Equality project by AIESEC organization at Ho Chi Minh City, Viet Nam: Contribute to project by being a Global Volunteer, Assisted in Viet Nam team of AIESEC.